<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Ardour_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="chap-Documentation-Ardour_Notes-Ardour_Live_Tools">
  <title>Ardour Live Tools</title>
  <para>
    These are some notes on how to modify and improve Ardour use as a live
    performance tool.
  </para>

  <section id="sect-Documentation-Ardour_Notes-Ardour_Live_Tools-Recording">
    <title>Recording</title>
    <para>
      What if any changes to recording would make Ardour better in as a live
      performance tool.
    </para>

    <para>
      Does manipulation of track controls like record, solo, mute etc need
      to be able to be automated to occur at bar/beat boundaries or perhaps
      queue until locate occurs etc
    </para>
  </section>

  <section id="sect-Documentation-Ardour_Notes-Ardour_Live_Tools-Editing">
    <title>Editing</title>
    <para>
      What if any changes to editing would make Ardour better in as a live
      performance tool.
    </para>

    <para>
      Muting regions using the mouse using Mute Tool
    </para>

    <para>
      Tools for manipulation of automation data at snap intervals for
      cutter/gapper type effects.
    </para>

    <para>
      Create range selection and add automation points at snap-to setting?
    </para>
  </section>

  <section id="sect-Documentation-Ardour_Notes-Ardour_Live_Tools-Looping">
    <title>Looping</title>
    <para>
      An important part of live performance is being able to easily
      manipulate loop points.
    </para>

    <para>
      Be able to audition while transport is rolling to control
      outs/headphones. Also being able to audition in sync.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section id="sect-Documentation-Ardour_Notes-Ardour_Live_Tools-Controllers">
    <title>Controllers</title>
    <para>
      Controllers play an integral part of live performance, so it will be
      necessary to have a fast and discoverable way to bind controllers to
      controls. This will be used for things like triggering changes in loop
      points. The location window might be a good place to allow binding
      controls for loop ranges.
    </para>

    <para>
      Add support for a specific external controller such as an android or
      iOS application?
    </para>
  </section>

  <section id="sect-Documentation-Ardour_Notes-Ardour_Live_Tools-Effects">
    <title>Effects</title>
    <para>
      Being able to bind controllers to effect parameters is important.
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>
